Guide to the Olive Hershey Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Olive Hershey Papers
1978-1988
03/2013-011
Hershey, Olive
4.50 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains drafts, revisions, editorial notes, and writings pertaining to the works of American novelist and poet Olive Hershey.
Biographical Information:
Olive Hershey was born in Houston, Texas in 1941, the daughter of Jacob W. and Olive Hershey. She attended Connecticut College from 1958-60; University of Texas at Austin, receiving a B.A. in 1968, M.A. in 1970, and Ph.D. in 1978; and University of Houston’s Creative Writing Program, receiving an M.A. in 1987. While at the University of Houston, Hershey studied under American novelist Donald Barthelme. She published Face Up, a book of poetry, in 1984 and the novel Truck Dance (originally her University of Houston thesis) in 1984.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Manuscripts (document genre); Typescripts
Personal Name:
Barthelme, Donald; Daugherty, Tracy; Hershey, Olive
Topical Term:
Authors, American -- 20th century
Acquisition Information:
Donated
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains drafts, revisions, editorial notes, and writings pertaining to the works of American novelist and poet Olive Hershey. The collection is divided into two series: Truck Dance and Other Works. Within each series, folders and items were left in the original order in which they were received from the author. Of particular interest are drafts of various chapters of Truck Dance containing revisions and notes from fellow American novelists Donald Barthelme, under whom Hershey studied while in the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston, and Tracy Daugherty, another student of Barthelme’s and graduate of the Creative Writing Program.
Detailed List of Contents
- Truck Dance
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains chapter and full drafts of Hershey’s novel Truck Dance. Many of the chapter drafts contain revisions and notes from American novelists Donald Barthelme and Tracy Daugherty. Folders were kept in their original order and original folder titles were used.
  - Chapter Drafts
    - Home (Little Egypt) - Tracy’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Other People’s Furniture - Tracy’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Bridge - Tracy’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Vernon - Tracy’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Bridge, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Truth Will Make You Free, But First It Will Make You Miserable - Tracy, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Bridge, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Every Last One - Tracy, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Espaldas Mojadas - Tracy’s revisions, Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mardi Gras, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Bridge, Out from Under, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Papa - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Money Man - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Vernon - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Refuge - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Home - Little Egypt - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Mardi Gras -Donald and Tracy revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Pigeon Shoot - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Every Last One - Cary, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mardi Gras - Cary, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Other People’s Furniture - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Sojourners - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Sisters - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Rafael, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Hog Killing, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - After the Equinox, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Synergy, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Border Patrol, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Refuge, Sisters, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Hog Killing, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Refuge, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Car, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Drifters, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Vernon, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - The Truth Will Make You Free, But First It Will Make You Miserable, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Drifters - Beverly (this actually looks like a bunch of chapters), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Oralee - New Beginning to Truck, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Pigeon Shoot, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Sojourners - Tracy’s revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Pigeon Shoot, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Combat Zone, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Out of the Combat Zone, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Sanctuary, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Hog Killing, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Border Patrol, Gary, Truck Song, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - How About You, Money Man?, Pyramid, Synergy, Gary, Vernon, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Synergy, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Pigeon Shoot - McDowell version, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Truck Song, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Hog Killing, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Pigeon Shoot - Last Revision, February 15, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Pigeon Shoot (Donald), Out from Under, Car, The Bridge, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Mardi Gras, Pudge, Every Last One, Little Egypt, The Truth Will Make You Free But First It Will Make You Miserable, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - The Truth Will Make You Free, But First It Will Make You Miserable, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - The Truth Will Make You Free, But First It Will Make You Miserable (final), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Border Patrol, Synergy, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - The Truth Will Make You Free, But First It Will Make You Miserable, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Hotel Jerome, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Encounter (later it’s Vernon), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mardi Gras, Home, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Out from Under, Vernon, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Crawdaddy, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Drifters - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Espaldas Mojadas, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - New Revision - Gary, Vernon, Caracara, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gary, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Border Patrol, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Truck Song, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gary, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Truck Stop, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Drifters 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Pigeon Shoot - Tracy, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hog Killing, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Encounter/Crawdaddy, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Pigeon Shoot - Don’s revisions, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Vernon, Gary, Truck Song, Pigeon Shoot, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Rafael, Combat Zone, Science in the Modern World, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Vernon, Cab and Wilma, Sisters, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Pigeon Shoot, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Miss Cornelia, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Every Last One, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Espaldas Mojadas, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - The Bridge, Pigeon Shoot, Hotel Jerome, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sanctuary, Combat Zone, Out of the Combat Zone, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Vernon, Car, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Rafael, Road Runner, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Road Runner, Gary, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Home, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Truth - comments for Beverly’s class, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - New Revision - Gary, Vernon, Caracara, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Sanctuary, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Roadrunner, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Wilma drafts and working notes, Road Runner, Combat Zone, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Every Last One, Out from Under, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Hog Killing - last revision, March 11, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Pigeon Shoot, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Refuge, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Full Drafts
    - Bound draft with notated bookmarks and handwritten notes, 1987 (Box 2, Item 1)
    - Bound draft, 1987 (Box 3, Item 1)
    - Bound “1st Draft” with edits inserted, 1987 (Box 3, Item 2)
    - Bound draft, 1987 (Box 3, Item 3)
    - Bound draft, 1987 (Box 3, Item 4)
    - Unbound draft with handwritten notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
    - Unbound printed draft with notes, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
    - Unbound printed draft, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Unbound partial draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Unbound draft, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
    - Unbound draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
    - Unbound draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
    - Unbound draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 15-17)
  - Notes and Research
    - Research articles, 1996, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Research clippings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cameron County Texas roadmap, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Novel notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Other Works
  - “From Seed bed to Second Cutting: The Story of Texas Rice” (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dobie Paisano Fellowship Application, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - “Horse Power,” Texas Monthly, March 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - “The Little Man and The Unicorn” unbound dissertation draft, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8-10)